Guide to the Verstille Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, 1754-1858, undated
  - Nancy Verstille
    - Incoming letters
      - Dabney, Abigail Mason
        - From Chelsea, 1820 October 23 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - From Boston, 1821 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - From Chelsea, 1821 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - From Salem
          - 1823 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 31)
          - 1823 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 31)
          - 1824 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 31)
          - 1824 August 11 (Box 2, Folder 31)
          - 1824 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 31)
          - 1824 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 31)
          - 1827 July 13 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Dabney, Elizabeth G.
        - From East Windsor, [1815] (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - From Salem
          - 1817 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - l818 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1818 July 22 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1818 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1818 August 6 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - From Cambridge
          - 1818 August 16 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1818 August 22 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - From Exeter, 1818 September 19 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - From Salem
          - 1818 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1818 November (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1818 November 30 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1818 December 24 (Box 2, Folder 32)
          - 1819 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - No place, 1819 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - From Salem
          - 1819 June 6 (Box 2, Folder 33)
          - 1819 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 33)
          - 1819 July 20 (Box 2, Folder 33)
          - 1820 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - From Chelsea
          - 1820 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 33)
          - 1821 April 20 (Box 2, Folder 33)
          - 1821 April 23 (Box 2, Folder 33)
          - 1821 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - From Salem
          - 1823 August 18 (Box 2, Folder 34)
          - 1827 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 34)
          - 1828 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - No place
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - From Salem
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - No place
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - John S. Barnes, East Windsor, 1858 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - E. Benjamin, Boston, 1818 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Phoebe Beyers, Milton, 1850 January 22 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Catharine Buck
        - New York (Box 2)
          - 1810 September 5 (Box 2, Folder 35)
          - 1812 July 9 (Box 2, Folder 35)
          - 1813 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 35)
          - 1814 February 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
          - 1814 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 35)
          - 1814 October 12 (Box 2, Folder 35)
          - 1814 December 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - No place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - George Buckham, New York, 1846 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - William Caton, Jr., New York, 1812 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - J. Dabney, Salem, 1807 May 27 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Margaret Dabney, Salem
        - 1828 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - 1828 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - 1831 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - 1834 November 2 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Ann Grant, East Windsor
        - 1839 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - 1847 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - 1849 October 8 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - N.W. Hall
        - Hartford, 1839 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - Brooklyn, 1840 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Eliza Horton, Providence, 1821January 30 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - E. Jackson, Jr., Middletown, 1832 August 29 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - James Killam, no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Tracy Liscome, no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - C.H. Ogden, Nassau Hall, 1811 November 16 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Mary Ogden, New Haven
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - N.P., no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Sarah Padelford, Taunton, 1799 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - T.W. Patton, New York, 1819 July 31 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Aaron Perrin, East Windsor, 1839 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Elizabeth H. Read, Salem, 1807 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - P. Robinson
        - Boston, 1814 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - No place, 1818 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - Boston, 1819 December 30 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - T. Tern, no place, [no year] February 22 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - H. Tudor
        - Middlebury, 1819 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - Providence, 1823 July 14 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Sophia Tudor
        - East Windsor (Box 2)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
          - Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - Providence, 1802 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - No place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Frank Turner, New Haven
        - 1839 November 16 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - 1839 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - 1840 November 21 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - 1841 July 8 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - M.C. Turner
        - New York, 1832 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - No place, 1834 August 29 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - New Haven, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - G. Verstille, New York, 1839 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - H.W. Verstille
        - New Haven, 1840 July 15 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - East Windsor, 1840 September 4 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Sheldon Verstille
        - New Haven, 1843 August 24 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - Buchanan, Texas, 1847 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - W.H. Verstille
        - New York (Box 2)
          - 1852 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 39)
          - 1853 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - Wardville, 1856 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - John G. Warren, Boston
        - 1818 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - 1818 October 13 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - 1820 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - 1826 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - C.W. Wooster, New York., 1816 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - L. Wooster, New York, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - N.W., no place
        - 1810 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Maria Wooster, New York, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - E.W., no place
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Outgoing letters, 1804-1821
      - Eliza Verstille, New Haven, 1804 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Maria Wooster, East Windsor, 1805 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Peter Verstille, East Windsor, 1808 December 21 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Charlotte Verstille, East Windsor, 1814 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Eliza Verstille, New York, 1814 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Charlotte Verstille, Patterson, N.J.
        - 1814 August 15 (Box 2, Folder 41)
        - 1814 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Eliza Verstille, Paterson, 1815 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Charlotte Verstille
        - Paterson, 1815 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 41)
        - East Windsor, 1815 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Lydia Wooster, East Windsor, 1816 January 2 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Charlotte Verstille
        - Boston, 1817 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - Salem, 1817 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - Boston, 1818 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - Salem, 1818 April 8 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - East Windsor, 1820 August 28 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Sheldon Verstille, East Windsor, 1821 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Charlotte Verstille, no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Tristram Verstille: incoming letter
    - J. Charlton, East Windsor, 1825 August 30 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - William Verstille: incoming letters
    - T. Allen, no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Richard Alsop, Middleton, 1788 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - William Gibbs, Philadelphia, 1781 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Bysell Haskell, East Windsor, 1802 April 22 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - John Knapp, Philadelphia, 1790 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - P. Lanman, Norwich, 1792 October 7 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - M. Liscome, Taunton, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Ann Olds, London, 1803 August 9 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Sam Ridgway, Boston, 1785 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - C. Richardson, no place, 1792 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Asa Spalding, Norwich, 1793 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - N. Tillinghast, Taunton, 1801 July 5 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Michael Todd, New Haven, 1792 December 22 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - E.W., no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - J. Wright, Philadelphia, 1791 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Copy of a letter from Wm. Verstille to Benj. Thanks, New York, 1787 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Thos. Wooster, New Haven, 1788 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Eliza Verstille: incoming letters
    - Mary Liscome, Taunton, [no year] June 6 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - S.R. Miller, Baton, 1804 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Peter Verstille, Salem, 1806 August 6 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Tristram Verstille, Robertville, 1812 August 26 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - William Verstille, Boston, 1803 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - W.H. Verstille, New York, Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - L. Wooster, New York
      - 1804 March 4 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - 1815 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Rebecca Verstille: incoming letter, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - H. W. Verstille, New Haven, 1840 July 15 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Sheldon Verstille: incoming letter, 1838 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Rev. Joseph Perry
    - Incoming correspondence
      - Nathaniel Appleton, Boston, 1768 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - George Beckwith, Lyme, 1770 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - James Dana, Wallingford, 1770 August 16 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Enoch Huntington, Middletown, 1783 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - S. Locke
        - Cambridge, 1772 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 46)
        - No place, 1773 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Samuel Ridgway
        - Boston (Box 2)
          - 1781 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 46)
          - 1783 January 2 (Box 2, Folder 46)
        - No place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Selleck Silliman, Fairfield, 1781 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Neh. Strong, New Haven, 1776 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - J. Troster, [place illegible], 1769 April 29 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Chauncey Whittelsey, New Haven
        - 1774 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 47)
        - 1783 February 14 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Unknown correspondent to Joseph Perry, Wethersfield, 1783 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - A Sermon, apparently of Rev. Joseph Perry, Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - Bushman, a Negro, West Springfield, 1792 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Joseph Perry, Sherburn, 1783 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous Letters
    - J. Beekman to J. Mitchell, Blooming Dale, 1812 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - L. Chester to Roswell Grant, 1792 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - John W. Church to Mr. Worthington, Angelica, 1839 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - M.J. Church to Mr. Ayrault, Triana, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - C. B. Everest to Jesse Charlton, Windham, 1817 June 24 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Betsey Felton to Mrs. James Felton, New Haven, 1839 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - E. Gaylord to Emeline Bowe, Fowlerville, 1830 November 9 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - E. Horton to Sophia Tudor, Providence, 1823 April 12 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Wm. Hoskins, to Ebenezer Grant, Windham, 1785 August 26 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - E. Jackson, Jr., to Henry Watson, Middletown, 1832 August 16 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - E. Liscomb to Miss Westerly, New York, 1840 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Mary Liscome to ?, no place, 1810 June 3 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Eliza Nivison to "Dear Aunt" [Verstille ?], New York
      - 1854 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - 1856 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - 1856 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - E. F. Reed, to W. F. Grant, New York, 1825 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Polly Robinson to ?, Boston, 1820 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Eliza [Smith] to Normand Smith, St. Louis, 1836 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Abiah Storrs, to Mary Potter, Watertown, 1786 March 13 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Mr. Warren to Elizabeth Dabney, no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Dorcas White to Warren Stebbins, no place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Capt. Woolsey to Wm. B. Hall, Champlain, 1804 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Unidentified, 1814, 1825-1839, undated (Box 2, Folder 50-51)
  - Business and other Papers
    - Receipt, Wm. Whitwell, Boston, 1756 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bill from Peter Verstille to John Robert, 1759 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Account of Peter Verstille with John Robert & John Gould, 1761 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bill of Benomi Olcott, East Windsor, 1763 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Receipt of Peter Verstille to Ebenezer Plummer, 1766 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bill of John Barrett & Sons to Ebenezer Grant & Sons, Boston, 1767 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Capt. Daniel Phelps, bill, Barbados, 1771 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Peter Verstille, Rate Bill, 1772 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bill of John Barrett & Sons to Ebenezer Grant & Sons, Boston, 1772 October 1 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Peter Verstille, account current with Hayley and Hopkins, 1772 December 31 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Account of estate of Peter Verstille with Smith & Coit, 1778 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Account of estate of Peter Verstille with Naomi Verstille, 1780 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Items bought from estate of Peter Verstille by Lt. Samuel Mears, 1780 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Paperbound book listing estates of Naomi Perry and Peter Verstille, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Receipt of Benomi Olcott, East Windsor, 1792 April 6 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Receipt of Abiel Gaylord, East Windsor, 1799 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Receipt of Jonathan Bissell, East Windsor, 1799 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Note of Wm. Verstille, 1800 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - I.O.U. of (?) Gaylord, East Windsor, 1807 April 8 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Receipt of (?) King, New York, 1812 November 27 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Account list, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - I.O.U. of P. Winthrop Grant, East Windsor, 1828 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - I.O.U. of P. Winthrop Grant, East Windsor, 1830 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Lock of the hair of Rev. Elijah Woolsey, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bill for Nancy Verstille, New York, 1853 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Calling card, poem, lists of furniture and foodstuffs, other papers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Folio and Oversize Items
    - ALS, E. Horton to Sophia Tudor, 1823 April 12 (Box 3)
    - Bill, Capt. Daniel Phelphs, 1771 (Box 3)
    - Account current, Peter Verstille, 1772 December 31 (Box 3)